# Mishaal Murawala

Portland, Oregon | +1 330-840-1903 | mishaalmurawala@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mishaalm/

I have been a Digital Transformation evangelist for a decade for companies I have worked at, especially in my roles at Keithley and Tektronix. I use the Six Sigma approach to add more "science" to the "art" of Marketing. As a digital leader, I have led systematic innovation, managed risk better, and yielded higher returns from project portfolios. In my recent roles, I was responsible for Digital Strategy and evolve the digital presence of the company to drive new growth and increase customer acquisition. I was responsible for driving significant sustainable improvements in the growth, lean, and digital leadership processes at Tektronix.

I am a strong professional skilled in:

- Omni-channel campaign strategy and Implementation and P&L Ownership
- Lean Six Sigma Methods Visual Management 5S/Kaizen Events Continuous Improvement Root Cause Analysis
- Marketing/ Business Operations, Analytics, and designing actionable dashboards
- Managing and mentoring direct reports
- Deep understanding of B2B customer journeys and personas
- Globally Minded, Culturally Aware

#### **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS:**

Mishaal Murawala LLC, Portland, Oregon

January 2019 - Current

**Digital Marketing Strategy, Demand Generation, and Marketing Operations Sr. Consultant** I help companies of any size with:

- Conducting a deep dive into business/ Marketing problems that need to be resolved. Once the problem has
  been articulated using SMART guideline, develop a digital marketing strategy and annual plan for assigned
  business lines, including crucial tactics and programs to deliver/exceed targeted goals and objectives
- Developing and leading a comprehensive marketing strategy, from 'top-of-the-funnel' awareness through conversion
- Tracking and optimizing the performance of digital marketing. Provide insights and analysis to determine lead
  quality and ROI from various digital marketing campaigns within and across multiple digital channels
- Developing targeting and analytics strategy to optimize user experience and engagement
- Ensuring integration of digital marketing strategy and tactics with other marketing efforts like Partner and offline marketing teams
- Ensure all digital projects go forward while effectively adhering to initiative goals, disseminating information for the creative and web development teams, and providing technical input on expectations for projects

Tektronix, Inc. (A Fortive Company), Portland, Oregon

December 2015 - December 2018

## **Global Digital Demand Generation Manager**

I was accountable for and led an internationally based team managing all digital lead generation activities globally for Tektronix and Keithley brand. As a part of Digital Marketing leadership both at Tektronix and Fortive, I used Lean six Sigma tools to develop a culture of operational excellence and process improvement by focusing on customers, employees, and processes.

- Managed 4M dollar annual budget and successfully generated 70% of Marketing order contribution from Digital Marketing activities (FY18) (~ 40% in FY16)
- Implemented a new content creation process where SEO was part of the content creation process and not an afterthought. I made SEO a company-wide initiative v/s. Running it as a digital marketing activity which resulted in 15-20% growth in expert topic content creation. This new content helped increase organic traffic in 2018 by 8% globally

# Mishaal Murawala

Portland, Oregon | +1 330-840-1903 | mishaalmurawala@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mishaalm/

- Being a part of digital leadership, I actively participated in numerous strategy development and execution through Policy/ Strategy Deployment initiatives (PD). Managed Operations and Policy Deployment reviews.
- Developed standard digital marketing practices in crucial digital marketing channels. Pioneered the use of
  Fortive Business System (FBS) lean manufacturing kaizen techniques to build a continuing, sustainable test and
  experimentation driven digital marketing process and culture
- Strategically directed and managed a full mix of paid, owned, and earned channels, including SEO, PPC, Social, display, content, and eCommerce (Amazon). Created a modern marketing framework that was used as standard work across the regions and business units.
- Led a culture change in the organization: By focusing on the right KPI's, changed the Marketing team's mindset away from lead obsession and helped develop a customer obsession

Tektronix, Inc. (A Fortive Company), Portland, Oregon

#### May 2014 - December 2015

### **Global Digital Project Manager**

Successfully programmed and launched a re-designed website for the business in concert with the new brand launch to offer a vastly improved customer journey and user experience. The redesigned website (on Drupal 6) had seen a 10-13% increase in on-page website conversions within the first three months of the launch. Other selected accomplishments include:

- Managed multiple projects from conception to completion using DMAIC, Lean, and Project Management methodologies to launch improvement projects and realize targeted benefits successfully. Project value ranged from \$50k to \$2 million
- Using daily management and other lean continuous improvement tools improved website NPS score from lower 20's to around 50's in fourteen months.
- Led teams across broad technical, Marketing, and business disciplines. Ensured that project objectives, specific goals, measures, and metrics are established before the start of the project
- Served as a critical cross-functional team leader in the web development team. Advised on strategies to best leverage our brand, content, and information via the web
- Facilitated Lean, Kaizen, Rapid Decision Making and other problem solving and improvement sessions across
   Marketing teams

Keithley Instruments, Inc. (A Tektronix Company), Cleveland, Ohio

#### August 2012 - May 2014

## **Digital Marketing and Web Operations Manager**

Analyzed and addressed opportunities and weaknesses in a company's digital marketing strategies and found that growth was stalled due to questionable ROI from Digital Marketing investments and process issues. I started grassroots marketing as an individual contributor with a \$0 budget. Revamped strategy to bring digital marketing to the forefront and developed plans for rapid revenue growth from indirect business. I managed three direct reports and a digital marketing budget of \$500k.

- Spearheaded global digital marketing strategies for Paid search, display and social leading to 10% year over year increase in raw lead generation
- Revitalized and executed search engine optimization (SEO) plans to increase the website traffic, which resulted in an increase in organic traffic by 5% and digital order contribution by 11%
- Overhauled web operations of 13 Keithley commercial websites and supervised web development teams (US
  and Beijing, China) in the testing and implementation of website functionality and user interface and
  optimization of cross-channel opportunities

# Mishaal Murawala

Portland, Oregon | +1 330-840-1903 | mishaalmurawala@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mishaalm/

Keithley Instruments, Inc. (A Tektronix Company), Cleveland, Ohio

June 2011 - July 2012

## **Business Analyst**

Joined the firm to work on a critical project that dealt with migrating the Sales Oracle setups from Keithley's CRM system into the Tektronix CRM system. Authored comprehensive management reporting, package well received by the management.

## **EDUCATION:**

# Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio

Master of Science (M.S.), Engineering Management (MEM)

# University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Information Technology (IT)

### **CERTIFICATION:**

Six Sigma Green Belt Certified (SSGBC)